汉娜·蒙塔娜：电影版
Hannah Montana: The Movie
-==本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献==-
欢迎登录www.Deefun.com
仅供学习交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
-==本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献==-
翻译： love0forever  WaitinZ  Lenefan
Spike Dai  pppker  Chester.Lee
-==本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献==-
校对： WaitinZ  loveforever  后期： love0forever
特别鸣谢： superjasson  LK歌词组
Hannah  Hannah  Hannah
Hannah! Hannah! Hannah!
谁总在后面推我
What is with all the pushing behind me?
票拿好  孩子们
Here you go, girls.
我是Miley Stewart  我们必须进去
It's Miley Stewart. We've got to get in there.
我们在贵宾名单上
Our names are on the list.
哎呀  怎么不早说呢  做梦吧  小滑头  下一个
Well, why didn't you say so? In your dreams, sweet cheeks. Next!
-不  不  名单上肯定有  我保证  -我们要两张
- No, no. They're on there. I promise. - We need two.
据我所知  你是唯一进不了自己演唱会大门的大明星
You are the only pop star I know who can't get into her own concert.
她刚才还在这里  我不知道她去哪儿了
She was just here. I don't know where she went.
-站住  -快走
- Stop! - Go!
快来人拦住那两个女孩
Somebody, stop those girls!
-开快一点  -不能再快了 这只是辆高尔夫球车
- Go faster! - I can't! This is a golf cart!
站住
Stop!
她们不能来这里  她们没有后台通行证
Those girls shouldn't be here! They don't have a backstage pass!
-你们搞什么  -以保安的身份命令你们站住
- What are you doing? - Stop in the name of Security!
-小心  -我需要支援
- Watch out! - I need backup!
快叫人来  哎哟
Call for backup! Whoa!
-太棒了  -太棒了
- Yes! - Yes!
站住
Stop!
-站住  -没关系  没关系  她们是和我一起的
- Please stop! - It's OK. It's OK. They're with me.
快点  快走
Come on. Go, go, go.
Hannah Montana 电影版 (又译:乖乖女是大明星)
Hannah Montana The Movie
爸
Dad.
怎么了
What?
该上场了  宝贝女儿
Showtime, baby doll.
-她来了  -好了  我们走
- She's on the move. - All right, let's go.
祝你好运  别搞砸了
Good luck! Don't mess up!
这边走  跟我来
This way. Follow me.
-来  -她过来了
- Come on. - She's coming right now.
好了  大明星准备上场了
All right, talent's on its way.
你每晚都是这么做的
You do that every night.
-我爱你  爸爸  -我也爱你  亲爱的
- Love you, Daddy. - I'm loving you right back, darling.
别忘了今天晚上轮到你洗盘子了
Don't forget it's your turn to do the dishes tonight.
我昨天晚上洗过了
I did them last night.
别和我讨价还价
Hey, don't give me no lip.
你可是想要在两个世界都是最棒的
You're the one that wanted the best of both worlds.
-Hannah  Hannah  Hannah  -小心头
- Hannah! Hannah! Hannah! - Watch your head.
大家一起来
Here we go, everybody! Whoo!
(Hannah Montana - Best of Both Worlds)
#哦  耶#
Oh, yeah.
#来吧#
Come on.
#豪华轿车已停在家门口#
You get the limo out front.
#时尚新潮  色彩艳丽#
Hottest styles, every shoe, every color.
#人出名后  真是有趣#
Yea when your famous it can be kinda fun.
#明明是你却无人认得#
It's really you but no one ever discovers.
#你一面与朋友谈笑风生#
In some ways you're just like all your friends
#一面在台上星光闪耀#
But on stage you're a star
#你在两个世界都是最棒的#
You get the best of both worlds.
#冷静放松  沉着应对#
Chill it out,take it slow,
#你用激情引爆全场#
then you rock out the show.
#你在两个世界都是最棒的#
You get the best of both worlds.
#二者融合  顿时发觉#
Mix it all together and you know that
#你在两个世界都是最棒的#
It's the best of both worlds.
#在两个世界都是最棒的#
The best of both worlds.
#电影首映礼  不见不散#
You go to movie premiers
#电台热歌榜  没你不行#
Hear your songs on the radio
#两个生活还真是奇妙#
Livin' two lives is a little weird
#不过学校里真的没人知道#
But school's cool cuz nobody knows
#来自小城的姑娘#
Yeah you get to be a small town girl
#背起吉他一切都不一样#
But big time when you play your guitar
#你在两个世界都是最棒的#
You get the best of both worlds.
#冷静放松  沉着应对#
Chill it out,take it slow,
#你用激情引爆全场#
then you rock out the show.
#你在两个世界都是最棒的#
You get the best of both worlds.
#在两个世界都是最棒的#
The best of both worlds.
#你在两个世界都是最棒的#
You get the best of both worlds.
#二者融合  顿时发觉#
Mix it all together and you know that
#你在两个世界都是最#
It's the best of both...
#都是最  都是最  都是最#
best of both, best of both, best of both...
#都是最棒的#
Best of both worlds.
咔  我们在发行之前搞定那个小瑕疵
Cut! We'll fix that last bit in post.
伙计们  收工了
That's a wrap, people.
-Hannah  你的表现一直很棒  -谢谢
- Hannah, as always, fabulous. - Thank you.
不  没事的  真对不起  我只是想见你
No. It's OK. I'm sorry. I just had to meet you.
我答应我的女儿们代她们向你问好
I promised my girls I'd say hi to you for them.
-嗨  -嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
她们甚至要我带来了些问题  耽搁您几秒钟
They even wrote out some questions, if you have a second.
哦  我的天  这太令人激动了  你介意我拍张照吗
Oh, my gosh, this is such a thrill. Do you mind?
-当然不  -你想都别想
- Not at all. - Don't even think about it.
-哦  Vita  没关系的  -任何事情只要和他扯上就有关系了
- No, Vita. It's OK. - Nothing about this man is OK.
你好  Osvald
Hello, Oswald.
你好  Vita  看起来还是和往常一样“可爱”
Hello, Vita. Looking lovely as ever.
恶心的假牙  你简直一天不如一天了
Icky teeth, really? Isn't that beneath even you?
Osvald Granger  《别致》杂志的主编
Oswald Granger, chief sleaze of Bon Chic magazine,
英国最臭名昭著的小报
Britain's most notorious tabloid.
而且我们乐意  以“ove”开头
And we would love, with a capital "ove,"
做一期封面特刊
to do a cover feature on
关于全球的Hannah  Montana现象
the global phenomenon that is Hannah Montana.
而他所说的“特刊”就是“毁了你的演艺生涯”
And by "feature" he means "career-ending expose."
“乡村女孩生活在受千万人爱戴的梦想中”
"Country girl living her dreams beloved by millions,"
这就是我们的底细
that's all we got.
这也是你能知道的全部  现在  滚出去
That's all you're gonna get. Now get out.
你不能责怪勇于尝试的人
Can't blame a bloke for trying.
你凭什么认为我们隐藏了什么
How could you even think we have something to hide?
-他什么都没看到  是吧  -我觉得他没有
- He didn't see anything, did he? - I don't think so.
很好  Hannah宝贝
Good. Hannah, honey,
你不能和任何人说话  除非我在你旁边
you can't talk to anyone unless I'm at your side.
我是你的代言人  你只需关注什么对你的演艺事业最好
I'm your publicist. You need to concentrate on what you do best
那就是唱出你的心声
which is singing your scrappy little heart out.
其他的事  让我来替你操心
Let me worry about everything else,
比如说保守你的小秘密
like making sure your little secret stays a secret.
有时候我真希望我能一直是Hannah
Sometimes I wish I could be Hannah all the time.
我和你一样  孩子
You and me both, kid.
让开道  猪头  站一边去  我们要过去
Out of the way, you jackals. Step aside. Coming through.
好了  别碰我们的大明星  站一边去
That's right, don't touch the pop star. Move aside.
比如说保守你的小秘密
...like making sure your little secret stays a secret.
秘密  什么秘密  挪开你的大屁股  你个老母牛
Secret? What secret? Move your bum, you old cow.
和我汇报下情况  Ozzie  别再让我失望了
Talk to me, Ozzie, and don't disappoint.
-很明显她有一个秘密  -很好  因为封面已经做好了
- Apparently there's a secret. - Good. Because the cover's ready.
但我还需要详细的故事
I just need the story to go with it.
去发掘这个秘密  她可是这个世界上最受欢迎的青少年
Find out that secret. She's the most popular teenager in the world.
所以我建议你去给我找到每一点每一滴
So I suggest you go out and find me every juicy,
有关Hannah  Montana那迷人而肮脏的私生活
sordid detail of Hannah Montana's outrageous, glamorous life.
好的  大家排好队  现在重新分队
All right. Line it up, people. We're going to choose new teams.
地板中央躺着个女孩儿呐  有人帮我一把吗
Dead girl in the middle of the floor. Anybody?
天大的好消息  Beyonce因双侧肺炎
Fabulous news: Beyonce has double pneumonia.
不得不放弃纽约音乐奖颁奖礼  你入选了
Has to drop out of the New York Music Awards. You're in!
这太棒了  无意冒犯Beyonce
That is great. Not for Beyonce.
我应该打个电话过去  但是我太高兴
I really should call. But, yes! I'm so excited!
我应该准备唱什么歌  穿什么衣服呢
What am I gonna sing? What am I gonna wear?
别急  别急  车和礼盒已经等在外面了
Great minds. The car and the box are already outside,
Hannah准备大采购了
so Hannah has to do a major shop now.
最后一次机会  快点
Last chance. Come on.
Miley  喂  我的生日聚会怎么办
Miley? Hello? What about my birthday party?
小型Hannah紧急事件  我会来的  我保证
Minor Hannah emergency. I'll be there, I promise.
是不是很好玩
Wasn't that fun?
是还不错  就是他们免费给我东西有点怪怪的
Yeah, but it feels weird having them give me stuff for free.
得了吧  你知道一张你在商店里购物的照片多值钱吗
Please. Do you know what a well-placed photo of you shopping is worth?
你是明星  是偶像
You're a star, an icon.
你要学会怎样愉悦的接触这个世界
You look at it, touch it, wear it, and the whole world has to have it.
他们属于你  Hannah  只要写上你的大名就是你的了
They owe it to you, Hannah. Name it and it's yours.
-真的吗  -我有太多东西要教你了
- Really? - I have so much to teach you.
如果她还不快点来  你就会错过你的飞机了
If she doesn't hurry up, you're going to miss your plane.
耶  说得对  失败者们  我去上大学了  田纳西大...
Yeah, that's right, losers! I'm going to college! Tennessee Universi...
-大学  -她到哪去了
- University. - Where is that girl?
-我不知道该挑哪一个  -挑一个  不需要  别紧张
- I can't decide. - Decide? No deciding. Too stressful.
全拿走  我们会把它们和那堆一起打包  女孩们
Take them all. We'll just add them to the pile. Girls.
手表  我真的需要一块新手表
Watches. I totally need a new watch.
这是现在的时间吗  我不敢相信
Is that the time? I can't believe it.
我们得走了  11条短信  Jackson
We got to go. Eleven messages. Jackson.
还有Lilly的礼物  Lilly肯定超喜欢那双鞋
Lilly's present. Lilly... would totally love those shoes.
-她肯定超喜欢这个  -对不起  我先看见的
- She will so love these. - I'm sorry. I saw these first.
帮我打包好行吗
Can you wrap these for me?
这个是我为我的最好的朋友买的  她今天过16岁生日
They're for my best friend. She's 16 today.
巧了  我也是为我最好的朋友买的
Funny, they're for my best friend, too.
我最好的朋友尺码是六码半
My best friend is a six and a half.
巧了  我最好的朋友也是6码半
Funny, my best friend's a six and a half, too.
Tyra Banks  这是唯一的一双了
Tyra Banks, that's our only pair.
-这可不巧了  你知道我是谁吗  -我知道你知道我是谁
- Not funny. Do you know who I am? - I know you know who I am.
-那又怎样  -又怎样
- So? - So?
-怎样  -怎样
-给我那只鞋子  -离我远点
- Give me that shoe. - Get away from me!
如果你想要  跳起来
You know what? If you want it, jump for it.
跳起来才能拿到鞋子  Hannah Montana
Jump for the shoe, Hannah Montana.
那好  给我
Fine. Gimme!
拿到了
Got it!
(Hannah Montana - The Good Life)
#每一天都是节假日#
Everyday's a holiday.
#我来教你怎样融入#
I'll show you how to work in,
#找到最适合你的方式#
To find the fit that's perfect.
我的  我的
Yes! Yes!
把鞋子还给我  女士
Give me my shoe, lady!
#我们过着好日子#
Living the good life,
#我们玩得很开心#
We have such a good time,
她的麻烦大了
She is so in trouble.
#噢  噢  喔  哦  喔  噢  好日子#
Oh, oh, whoa, oh, whoa, oh, the good life.
不  你没拿到  Hannah Montana
No, you didn't! Hannah Montana!
#噢  噢  喔  噢  喔  我过着好日子#
Oh, oh, whoa, oh, whoa, I'm living the good life.
-是我的了  -我很感激你能把我拉起来
- Yes! - I appreciate you helping me up,
但是你没帮我抢到鞋子  我很失望
but I don't appreciate you not helping me with this.
#好日子#
The good life.
放松  开玩笑  你见过我老爸吗
Relax? Are you kidding me? Have you met my dad?
错过和Jackson道别  我老爸会把我扔出去的
He is not gonna shake off me missing saying goodbye to Jackson.
笑一笑  Hannah  你看上去美极了
Give us a smile. You look amazing.
谢谢  我们得走了
Thank you. We got to go.
我没抢到那双鞋子  我是这个世界上最糟糕的朋友了
And I didn't even get the shoes. I am the worst friend in the world.
是他
It's him.
Oswald  甩掉他
Oswald. Step on it!
我不能以Miley的模样下车
I cannot get out of the car looking like Miley,
也不能以Hannah的身份现身Lilly的聚会
and I cannot show up at Lilly's party looking like Hannah.
你们要去哪
Where are you headed?
嗨  谢谢你  谢谢
Hi! Thank you. Thank you.
嗨  Lilly  什么事
Hey, Lilly. What's up?
Miley  我们从12岁起就开始谈论这个聚会了  你在
We've talked about this party since we were, like, 12. Where...
-嗨  你好吗  你在哪儿  -我快来了
- Hi! How are you? Where are you? - I'm almost there.
她把电话挂了
She hung up on...
你在哪  大家都在等
Where are you? Everybody's waiting...
-对不起  你打错了  -Miley
- Sorry, wrong number! - Miley!
两份冰沙  谢谢  Mliey在哪儿  我们没看见她
Two smoothies, please. Where's Miley? We haven't seen her.
刚和她通电话了  她马上就到
Just spoke with her. She'll be here any second.
Rico  蛋糕顶上的洞是干什么用的
Rico, what's this hole at the top of the cake?
那是装用来压缩气体的高压电动螺线管的
It's a high-pressure electro-pneumatic solenoid on it.
有铜质安全阀门  能提供每平方英尺150磅的压力
It's 150 pounds per square inch with a brass safety-check valve.
那时只要我一按这个按钮  砰  先是焰火
Then I just hit this button and bam! Sparklers go off,
接着  写着“Lilly生日快乐”的旗子会从蛋糕顶上冲出来
and a "happy birthday, Lilly" banner shoots out the top of the cake.
再次证明  Rico是个天才
Once again... Rico is a genius.
等等  这是私人聚会
Hold it! This is a private event.
只允许受邀宾客进入  你没听到吗  停
Guests only! What did I tell you? Stop!
-笑一个  -不许拍照
- Smile. - No pictures.
这就是我称之为Lilly  哇哦
That's what I call a Lilly... Wow.
是Hannah Montana
It's Hannah Montana!
那是Hannah  Montana吗
Is that Hannah Montana?
朋友们  我来这儿是为了  等等
Guys, I'm only here... Wait!
生日快乐
Happy birthday to...
我想向我的头号大粉丝Lilly说生日快乐
I want to say happy birthday to my number one fan, Lilly.
她在那里  在那里
She's over that way. She's over that way.
生日快乐  Lilly  生日快乐
Happy birthday, Lilly. Happy birthday.
对不起  我没得选择  我会补偿你的  我保证
I'm sorry. I had no choice. I'll make it up to you, I promise.
你永远永远永远也无法补偿我
You will never, ever, ever make it up to me.
我真的很抱歉
I'm sorry.
来一首  来一首  来一首  来一首
Sing, sing, sing, sing, sing.
疯狂  疯狂  疯狂  疯狂  疯狂
Crazy, Crazy, Crazy, Crazy, Crazy.
你们都会唱《Let's Get Crazy》吧
Uh, you guys know the words to Let's Get Crazy?
好的  那么  我们开始吧
All right, then, here we go!
准备好了吗  让我们开始吧
You ready? Here we go.
(Hannah Montana - Let's Get Crazy)
#生活像个派对  邀你快来参加#
Life is just a party so come as you are
#只顾收拾打扮  别忘带上吉他#
Dress it up or dress it down, don't forget your guitar, yeah
#勇敢面对一切  热情也能传染#
Just be courageous, 'cause style's contagious
#每个人都可以  做个超级明星#
Everyone can rock out like a superstar
#疯狂起来#
Let's get crazy
#舞动起来#
Get up and dance
#尽情摇摆  做你自己#
Take a swing, do your thing
#这绝对值得一试#
It's worth taking a chance
#疯狂起来#
Let's get crazy
#耶  脚抬高#
Yeah, just kick up your heels
#别错过  大声叫#
Don't miss out, time to shout
#真诚对待#
Always keeping it real
#疯狂起来#
Let's get crazy
#疯狂#
Crazy
Lilly  Lilly  我们有蛋糕
Lilly! Lilly, we got cake!
等等  生日女孩儿  我有几个问题
Hold up. Wait. Birthday Girl, I have some questions.
Hannah真的已经四十三岁了吗
Is it true Hannah's really 43 years old?
她唱歌对口型吗  她是在纳什维尔长大的吗
She lip syncs? Grew up in Nashville?
更准确地说是在Crowley Corners的麦田里长大的
More like a cornfield in some place called Crowley Corners.
真的吗  Crowley怎么写
Really? How do you spell "Crowley"?
生日快乐  Lilly Truscott  祝福送给她
It's Lilly Truscott, everybody! Happy birthday.
那儿有蛋糕
We got cake over there.
说得跟真的似的
Just like it sounds.
-Lilly  -Oliver  快
- Lilly! - Oliver? Quick!
把蛋糕里的横幅弄出来  我们不能让Lilly走
Light the cake. We're gonna stop Lilly from leaving.
蛋糕  不  我还没准备好呢
Cake? No, I'm not ready yet!
快看啊  我们有蛋糕
Come on! We have cake!
不好意思
Sorry.
Lilly  拜托  接电话吧
Lilly, please pick up.
-看见了吗  -当然  我知道  铺天盖地
- Did you see this? - Yeah, I know. It's everywhere.
这是不是  很恐怖  坏Hannah
Isn't it... horrible. Bad Hannah.
我和她得稍微谈一谈了
She and I need to have a little conversation.
现在吗  可是她已经准备好去纽约了呀
Now? But she's getting ready to go to New York.
她没告诉你吗  那儿有一个很棒的机会
Didn't she tell you? There's an amazing opportunity.
没错  我知道纽约的事情
Yeah, I know about New York.
我在电子邮件里已经看到了  门儿都没有
I got CCed in an e-mail. Not happening.
她和我要飞到田纳西去给她姥姥Ruby祝寿
She and I are flying to Tennessee for her Grandma Ruby's birthday.
她没告诉你吗
Didn't she tell you?
鞋子大战  你竟然能卷入了一场该死的鞋子大战
A shoe fight! You got into a stinking shoe fight?
我认为明明是我先看见那双鞋的
In my defense, I totally saw those shoes first.
知道吗
You know what?
这根本完全绝对毫无疑问地不是一个理由
This is absolutely, T-totally, without a doubt unacceptable.
你最近的一切行为举止都是这样
Which pretty much describes all of your behavior lately.
做事儿根本不考虑你哥  还在Lilly的生日派对上羞辱她
Standing up your brother? Humiliating Lilly at her own party?
我知道我都搞砸了  我很抱歉  但是我现在不想谈这个
I know. I screwed up. I'm sorry, but I can't talk about this now.
我要去纽约  参加音乐奖颁奖典礼
I got to go to New York. It's the music awards.
就连你姥姥的生日都可以无视了
So your grandmother's birthday doesn't matter?
这是两码事儿  你心里清楚
Dad, this is totally different and you know it.
好了  Robby Ray先生
Now, Robby. Mr. Ray.
Montana父亲  Hannah不去纽约真的是行不通的
Father Montana, Hannah not going to New York is really not an option.
-她叫Miley  -Miley会赶回去的
- Her name is Miley. - Miley'll be back before she leaves.
她是个超级巨星  如果她需要的话我能给她弄一架私人飞机来
She's a superstar. I can get her a private jet if she wants.
没错  我一直想要一架
Yes! I've always wanted one of those.
老天爷啊
For gosh sakes.
好吧  你赢了
Fine. You win.
不过你听见我们的超级明星说什么了吗  她要一架飞机
But you heard our superstar. She needs a jet.
-真的吗  -我喜欢你的态度
- Really? - I like your thinking.
这个得花些时间来安排
It will take some time to arrange,
不过我就得先去纽约安排行程了
but I'll go ahead to New York and set up the meet and greet.
下一次  你最好弄一架卫生间大点的飞机来
Next time, you might want to demand a jet with a bigger bathroom.
你为啥现在就打扮成Hannah的装束了
Why in the heck you getting all Hannahed up?
Hannah走下舷梯的时候就会有记者拍照了啊
The Hannah steps off the plane photo op. You know.
还有气球  礼车  尖叫的粉丝
The balloons, the limos, the screaming fans.
就像Vita说的一样 “这就叫宣传活动”
Like Vita says, "It's all about the publicity. "
是啊  Vita总是有那么多好建议
Yeah. That Vita's just full of good advice.
满脑子都是
Absolutely full of it.
你好  纽约
Hello, New York!
看样子你的礼车来了
Looks like your limo's here.
这家伙够美吧
Ain't she a beaut?
田纳西  老子来了
Yee doggies. Tennessee.
爸  听我说
Dad, come on.
没错  我是应该记着姥姥的生日的
Yeah, maybe I should've remembered Grandma's birthday.
-我记着呢  -Jackson 别插嘴
- I did. - Jackson, not now.
爸  求你了
Dad! Please,
再过不到三个小时Hannah Montana内就应该
Hannah Montana needs to be walking down the red carpet
走在纽约的红地毯上
in New York in less than three hours.
Miley  你原来只是想去唱歌而已
Miley, all you ever wanted to do was sing.
Hannah这个身份让你在唱歌的同时还能过正常的生活
Hannah let you do that and still have a normal life.
这是你的梦想  还记得吗
That was the dream, remember?
这才是我们当初设计出这个形象的目的
That's why we created her in the first place.
老实说  我不知道她现在还有什么意义
Being honest, I don't know what she's about anymore.
-你说什么  -我想说我觉得我们可以结束这一切了
-What are you saying? -I'm trying to say I think we might be done.
你不能把Hannah从我身上夺走
You can't take Hannah away from me.
是么  我就准备这么做呢
Really? Because that's what I'm doing.
不行  快把卡车停下  我不能这么做  我要回家
No! Stop the truck. I'm not doing this. I want to go home.
把车停下
Stop the truck!
你已经回家了  看看你的周围
You are home. Look around you.
Hannah就是我的一切
Hannah means everything to me.
这正是问题所在之处
That right there might be the problem.
你的意思是  我再也不能做Hannah了
You're saying I can never be Hannah again?
两个星期以后再问我
Ask me again in two weeks.
现在让我们看看那个乡村女孩还活着没有
Right now let's see if a country girl still exists.
-两个星期  -你就把它当成是戒一戒当Hannah的瘾
- Two weeks? - Think of it as a Hannah detox.
把假发摘下来  回到卡车里去
Take that wig off and get back in the truck.
不  我不上车  绝对不上
No. I'm not getting back in the truck. No way.
我不上车  爸爸
I'm not getting back in the truck, Dad.
不管你愿不愿意  我都要去纽约
I'm going to New York whether you like it or not,
我不上  喔
and I'm not... Whoa!
还给我  你这个脏兮兮的小
Give that back, you mangy little...
你看看  小姑娘都不认识她自己的马了
Look at that. Girl don't even recognize her own horse.
实在太可悲了
Now that truly is sad.
蓝仔
Blue Jeans?
我们屋里见  沿着路往前走一英里就到了
Meet us at the house. Just about a mile up the road.
别忘了你的行李箱
Don't forget your suitcase.
我真觉得你的确变得不一样了
In my defense, you do look different.
你是不是把你的尾巴处理了一下
Did you do something to your tail?
好孩子  好了  帮我个忙
Good boy. All right, now. Help me out.
别动
Hold still.
蓝仔
Blue Jeans!
嗨  你还好吗
Hi. You all right?
蓝仔对待陌生人不是很友好
Blue Jeans doesn't really take well to strangers.
尤其对一点也不土  还亮丽十足的人
Especially not dirty, sparkly ones.
我知道  他是我的马
I know. He's my horse.
Miley
Miley?
是我  Travis
It's me. Travis?
Travis Brody  我们一起上的一年级
Travis Brody. We were in the first grade together.
我和你一起去Earl叔叔的农场游泳
Me and you went to your Uncle Earl's farm and swam
-还把毒葛弄得满身  -我记得你  好吗
- and got poison oak all over our... - I remember you, OK?
我还记得你把我头朝下悬着往井里放
I also remember you hanging me headfirst down a well.
是啊  我猜我后来还真是喜欢上你了
Yeah. I guess I had a pretty big crush on you back then.
不过别担心
But don't worry about it.
都过去了
I'm over it.
那就行
Good to know.
也不经常回来看看了  是不
Don't come around too often anymore, do you?
够经常的了
Often enough.
我听说自从你妈去世以后你就没回来过几次了
Only a couple times since your ma died that I've heard about.
那么你这次要呆多长时间
So how long are you staying?
-两个星期  -哈
- Two weeks. - Ha!
-祝你好运  -此话怎讲
- Good luck with that. - What's that supposed to mean?
考虑到你穿的穿着打扮
Considering what you're wearing
和你不会骑到你的马上的事实
and the fact that you couldn't get back on your horse,
我猜你是到加利福尼亚当大小姐去了
I'm guessing you went California on us.
我才没有  你根本不了解我和加利福尼亚
I have not. You don't know anything about me or California.
让我猜猜  那些名流和你我一样都是普通人吧
Let me guess, celebrities are just regular folk like you and me.
-有些是  -哦  啊哈
- Some are. - Oh. Uh-huh.
你  呃  认识哪些名人嘛
You, uh... you actually know any?
我认识Hannah Montana
I know Hannah Montana.
Hannah Montana  真的吗
Hannah Montana? Really?
是啊  我
Yeah. I...
实际上她冲浪的时候我救过她的命
I practically saved her life surfing the other day.
她欠我个大人情  我们就像  就像是最好的朋友
She owes me big time. We're like... We're like best friends.
嗬  最好的朋友
Huh. Best friends.
我猜他们都在里面等你呢
I guess they're all waiting for you inside.
我把蓝仔带走
I'll take Blue Jeans, put him away.
-你不用这么做  -这其实是我的工作
- You don't have to do that. - It's kind of my job.
这个夏天我给你姥姥干活
I've been working for your grandma for the summer.
一般情况下这时候应该有个人说“谢谢”
This is usually about the time someone would say "thank you."
-我本来马上就要说的  -不用了
- I was getting there. - No need.
回见  爱笑的Miley
See you round, Smiley Miley.
还记得吗  他以前就这么叫你  爱笑的Miley
Remember? That's what he used to call you. Smiley Miley.
我记得
I remember.
(Rascal Flatts - Backwards)
#我们坐在那儿聊天  谈到如果一切回转#
We sat there and talked about how it would be.
#时光倒流  那些事情还能否#
If we could just rewind it all and go back in
#称心如意#
T-I-M-E
#你的房回来了  你的狗回来了#
You get your house back, You get your dog back
#你最好的朋友Jackson回来了#
You get your best friend Jackson back
#你的卡车回来了  你的头发回来了#
You get your truck back, You get your hair back
#你的工作一个接着一个回来了#
Ya get your first and second jobs back
#你前门廊的铃铛叮个铃个铃#
Your front porch swing goin' ding-a-ling-a-ling
#你的珠宝首饰  钻石戒指#
Your bling bling bling and a diamond ring
#你的农场  你的粮仓  你的小船  你的摩托#
Your get your farm and the barn and the boat and the Harley
#你那只叫查理的老猫咪#
That old black cat named Charlie
#有点疯狂  有点凌乱  有点离奇#
It sounds a little crazy a little scattered and absurd
#倒着放首乡村歌曲  这一切全都归你#
But that's what you get when you play a country song backwards
我的Miley回来了
I got my Miley back!
快来  Miley  下一段你来接
Come on, Miley, take the next verse.
来吧
Come on.
你的狗回来了  你的房回来了
Get your dog back and your house back...
我想把我的生活要回来  爸
I want my life back, Dad.
对不住大家了  嘿
Sorry. Sorry, everybody. Hey.
生日快乐  姥姥
Happy birthday, Grandma.
好啊  我刚刚才吹灭蜡烛
Well, I just blew out my candles,
我的愿望就实现了
and I already got my birthday wish.
过来  小宝贝儿  噢
Come here, sweet thing. Ohhh.
我都想死你了
I have missed you more than you can imagine.
谢谢你
And thank you.
谢谢你送我这个  我太喜欢了
Thank you so much for this. I just love it.
只有一个国王
There's only one King,
这个位置我都留了好长时间了
and I have been saving him a place of honor.
你策划了多久啊
How long have you been planning this?
找这东西肯定花了你老长时间了吧
Must have taken you forever to find it.
那是  几个星期以来我就没想别的
Apparently, I've thought of nothing else for weeks.
最不用放在心上的就是你姥姥的心情
Hurt your grandma's feelings
和假发底下那个真实的你了
and a chewed-up wig'll be the least of your worries.
嘿  Chuck叔叔  该吃蛋糕了
Hey, Uncle Chuck. Listen, it's time for cake.
我去收餐盘  你去收叉子
I'll collect the supper plates, you pass out the forks.
这是跟大家打招呼的好机会
Give you a chance to say hi to a few folks.
-还记得Derrick堂哥吗  -这老鼠是哪儿来的
- You remember Cousin Derrick. - What's with the rat?
这是只雪貂  它叫Harlow
Ferret. Harlow.
-回家真好  -是啊
- Good to be home. - Yeah.
盘子要给我吗
Got any plates for me?
帮我个忙  去向那边的Lorelai做个自我介绍
Do me a favor. Introduce yourself to Lorelai over there.
她是新来的  还有点害羞
She's new and a little shy.
你又对牵红线这种事儿感兴趣了  是不是
You ain't up to your matchmaking again, are you?
-我  哪有  -那就好
- Me? Never. - That's right.
我就当成是你不想让任何人觉得自己是个局外人
Then I reckon it would be a shame for anybody to feel left out.
打扰了  要我收什么东西吗
Excuse me. Got anything for me?
我不知道  你确定你能端住吗
I don't know. Are you sure you can handle it?
我能端住的东西多了  会让你大吃一惊的
You'd be amazed at what I can handle.
我觉得我们好像没见过面  我是Robby Ray
I don't believe we've met. I'm Robby Ray.
告诉你我会让你吃惊的
Told you you'd be amazed.
我搞定了  没有多严重  女士们先生们
I got it. It's not that bad, ladies and gentlemen.
噢  我的老天爷
Oh, Lord!
-搞定  -噢  不
- Howdy! - Oh, no.
我的妈呀  告诉大家一个好消息
Whee doggies! Great news, everybody.
猫王活得好好的
Elvis is alive and well.
(Rascal Flatts - Bless the Broken Road)
#每一个久违的梦  都让我想起久违的你#
Every long lost dream lead me to where you are
#有些人伤过我的心  却好似天上的北极星#
Others who broke my heart they were like northern stars
#指引我前行的路  投入你温暖的怀抱#
Pointing me on my way into your loving arms
#我知道这有多么真切#
This much I know is true
#上帝定会保佑我  历尽千辛找到你#
That God blessed the broken road that led me straight to you
#时光流转  岁月如梭#
I think about the years I spent, just passing through
我一直觉得我应该把壁纸换掉
I keep thinking I should change the wallpaper,
不过这是你妈妈在你这么大的时候挑选的
but your mom picked this out when she was about your age.
我挺喜欢的
I like it.
以前你特喜欢来看我  理由各种各样的
You used to like a lot of things about coming to see me.
-姥姥  -没关系
- Grandma... - It's OK.
我知道你不是因为我的原因才不回来的
I know it's not personal.
-我只是很想念我的Miley  -为什么每个人都这么说
- I just miss my Miley. - Why does everyone keep saying that?
也许这个问题得问你自己
Maybe you should be asking yourself that question.
树上有只毛毛虫  不知以后会怎样
Caterpillar in a tree. How you wonder who you'll be
哪怕总是走不远  你也一直有梦想
Can't go far.  But you can always dream
以前你爸爸每天晚上都这么对你说
Your daddy used to say that to you every night.
现在再也不会了
Not so much anymore.
#上帝定会保佑我  历尽千辛找到你#
That God blessed the broken road that led me straight to you
Miley  太阳晒屁股啦
Miley! Rise and shine!
拯救Hannah Montana行动开始
Commence Operation Save Hannah Montana.
早安  睡得好吗  我早就醒了
Morning! Sleep well? I've been up for hours.
我去鸡舍拿些鸡蛋怎么样
How about I go feed the chickens and grab some eggs?
就像我经常说的
You know, like I always say,
早餐没鸡蛋 一天没营养
ain't nothin' better than farm-fresh eggs for breakfast!
刚刚走过去那个村姑是谁
Who in the Sam Heck was that?
来吧  咯吱-咯吱-咯吱-咯吱
Here, chick-chick-chick-chick.
离我远...
Get away from...
你觉得她要过多久才想起来把桶给放下
How long you think before she figures out to put down the bucket?
喔  我得...
Oh, I'm gonna...
(Miley Cyrus - Don't Walk Away)
#我一整天都在原地绕圈#
I've been runnin in circles all day long
#我无法呼吸但仍坚定前行#
I'm out of breath but I'm still going strong
#不管别人怎么说  我都要得到你#
I'm gonna get'cha yeah no matter what they say
#你以为我迷路了  其实我能找对方向#
You think I'm losing but I always get my way
#当我对你说话时别走开#
Don't walk away when I'm talkin to you
#你的坏脾气此时不该来#
This ain't no time for your bad attitude
#别给我摆出那副烂表情#
Don't gimme, that face
#真正的追逐才刚刚展开#
When you know I'm really down for the chase
#因为我真的全身心投入#
Cause' my hearts already in it
#而且我将永不认输#
And I'm never gonna quit it
#当你最终明白的时候#
When you finally gonna get it
#请别走开#
Don't walk away
很好  拿到了  一个绝对新鲜的鸡蛋
All right. Here we go, one farm-fresh egg.
-你们不等我吃早饭吗  -宝贝  我们等你了
- Y'all couldn't wait? - Darling, we waited,
不过我们总不能等一辈子吧
but eventually we had to get on with the rest of our lives.
亲爱的  去把自己收拾干净
Get yourself cleaned up, honeybee.
我等会儿带你去农贸市场
I'm taking you to the farmers' market.
行
Yay.
噢  Robby Ray  我的水槽需要修一修了
Oh, Robby Ray, my gutters need fixing.
而且我的卡车还发出你这辈子都不能忍的噪音
And my truck is making a noise you just don't want to hear.
我马上解决
I'm on it.
如果需要任何帮助  就去和工头说
If you need any help, talk to the foreman.
可能还在菜地里
Might be down by the vegetable patch.
明白
Gotcha.
但是别踩烂我的南瓜  它们可是要得奖的
But don't go squashing my squashes. They're prizewinners.
看起来你做得比我好
Looks like you beat me to it.
Lorelai
Lorelai?
呃  Ruby没说  你就是工头
Uh, Ruby didn't... You're the foreman?
-说的就是我  -就是说  你也住在这里
- That would be me. - So that means you're living here, too?
你很会装傻嘛
You're good at this.
我就住在那边
That's me, right over there.
我想有个新的开始  而且我想Ruby觉得
I was looking for a fresh start, and I guess Ruby thought
我和这个农场都需要有人照料  所以...
that both me and the farm could use some looking after, so...
没错  她确实喜欢把什么都搅和到一起
She does like putting things together, that's for sure.
Lorelai  工头
Lorelai. The foreman.
用不着我了
I'll be dang.
好了  各位
All right, you guys.
我很荣幸地为大家介绍Tammy Wynette
I'd like to introduce you all to Tammy Wynette.
她是全世界跑得最快的双足动物
She is the fastest two-legged animal in the world.
她不能飞  不能游  不过她当然会
She can't fly, she can't swim, but she sure can...
咬人  要当心
...bite. Be careful.
我们之前谈过这个的  难道你想去看看小吃店
We talked about this. Unless you want to see ostrich burgers
菜单上面的鸵鸟汉堡吗
on the menu at the snack bar...
这里交给我了  你去喂Pear小姐吧
I'll take it from here. Go feed Miss Pearl.
不  我讨厌Pearl小姐
No, I hate Miss Pearl.
好了  孩子们  谁想去看看真实的  活蹦乱跳的
All right, kids. Who wants to see a real live...
鳄鱼
...alligator?
放开我
Let go!
救命
Help!
这么巨大的奶头要做什么用
What's with the giant udder?
这可是你在贝佛利山庄看不到的景观
That is something you don't see in Beverly Hills.
老Crowley死了以后把这片牧场留给了镇上
Old Man Crowley died and left the town the meadows,
你能看到的这些都是
pretty much everything you can see.
但是我们没有足够的钱去交税了
But we don't exactly have enough for the taxes,
所以我一直在帮忙  筹了几次款
so I've been helping organize a fundraiser or two.
太过分了  开发商拼命圈地  跟秃鹫没什么两样
It's just awful. Developers circling like vultures.
还说要建什么公寓大楼  购物中心
Talking about putting up apartment buildings. Shopping malls.
一个购物中心  真的吗
A mall? Really?
如果他们得逞  这里就不再有平坦开阔的土地了
If they have their way, there won't be any open land left.
嘿  Ruby  来一份这个吗  小姑娘
Hey, Ruby. How'd you like one of those, young lady?
-谢谢  -走吧 Miley
- Thank you.  - Come on, Miley.
-这里会有Bloomie's精品百货吗  -我们还有很多事要做
- Would there be a Bloomie's? - We've got work to do.
抱歉
Sorry.
-你看到的就是未来   -谢谢
- You're looking at the future. - Thank you.
我是认真的  这个人的所有一切都让我反胃
I swear, everything about that man irks me.
-早上好  Ruby小姐  -您早
- Morning, Miss Ruby. - Morning.
看来你把小孙女也带上了
See you got your granddaughter with you.
-是啊  没错  -她都长这么大了
- Yeah, sure do. - Ain't she grown some.
吃少喝少居然能有这样的好效果
Amazing what a little food and water will do.
很高兴和您聊天
Nice chatting.
等我们干完这些  也许咱俩可以一块去买点东西
When we finish, maybe you and I can do a little shopping.
去那儿买  谢谢  还是算了
In there? No, thanks. I'm good.
听着  小妞  在家里或许你是Hannah Montana
Look, missy. You may be Hannah Montana back home,
可是在这我们都是穿马裤皮靴的粗人  所以
but here we're britches and boots. And...
如果你还觉得不满意
...if that ain't good enough for you,
那么你大概只好收拾行李走人
maybe you should just pack up and git.
你也许能蒙过你老爸
You might be fooling your daddy,
但你绝对蒙不了我
but you sure as heck ain't fooling me.
好了  抱歉我唠叨这么多
Now, I'm sorry for fussing at you,
不过  我只是觉得如今你有一个
but... I just think you should consider yourself lucky that,
能称之为家的地方  你应该感到幸运
for the time being, you have a place like this to call home.
我确实觉得
I do.
对不起
And I'm sorry.
我知道
I know you are.
来吧
Come on!
-在这里吗  -是的
- Right here? - Yeah.
然后  把这个西瓜切开当样品
Now... slice up this watermelon for samples.
你现在看到的是Crowley牧场的未来
You're looking at the future of Crowley Meadows.
我要把我的火气收起来然后用到合适的地方
I'm going to take this mood of mine and put it to good use.
免费品尝  这个给你  美女
Free samples! Here you go, girls.
Ruby  你想募捐多少次都可以
Ruby, you can have as many fundraisers as you want,
但你阻止不了时代的步伐
but you are not going to stop progress.
我可不会管把Mills水塘变成垃圾场叫做时代的步伐
Turning Mills Pond into a landfill is not what I call progress.
好吧  很显然...
Well, obviously...
我很快就回来
I'll be right back.
-早上好  -早上好
- Morning. - Morning.
呃  你认识这女孩吗
Um, do you know this girl?
当然  Hannah Montana  我又不是山顶洞人
Sure, Hannah Montana. I don't live under a rock.
噢  显然不是  不是
No, obviously not. No, no.
-想吃点试试吗  -就吃一点
- You wanna try something? - A bit of that.
可以
OK.
很棒  很美味
That's very nice. That's delicious.
-我马上回来  -也许她用了另一个名字
- Uh, I'll be right back. - Maybe she used a different name.
-我可不这么想  -总有人知道她住在哪儿
- I don't think so. - Somebody must know where she lives.
-不行 我得走了   -好吧 谢谢
- No. I got to go. - OK. Thank you!
-Miley 来帮我...  -起来
- Miley, help me get this... - Get up.
帮忙把他拉起来  把他弄走
Help him up now. Let's get him out of here.
帮帮这个可怜的人  你还好吗
Help me with this poor man. Are you OK?
-我非常 非常抱歉  -没关系的
- I'm terribly, terribly sorry. - Honey, you are so forgiven.
你人真好  真的很好
You're too kind. No, really.
你年龄正好  你认识Hannah Montana吗
You're about the same age. You know this Hannah Montana?
Hannah Montana  谁不认识Hannah Montana  她很有名
Hannah Montana! Who don't know Hannah Montana? She's famous.
她对每个人都说她来自这个破地方的一个小牧场
She's telling everyone she's from this little patch of nowhere,
可是谁都没见过她
but no one's ever seen her.
我见过她  以前见过  认识她  以前认识
I seen her, saw her, know her, knew her.
-你是第一个  -我认识整个Montana家的人
- You're the first one. - I know all the Montanas-es.
你知道我在哪儿能找到他们吗
Do you know where I could find them?
当然  往镇上南边走5英里
Sure. You go about five miles south of town,
第一个岔路往右拐
turn right at the first crick.
-第二个弯道左拐  -就找到了
- Left at the second crook. - There you are.
找到了
There you are.
-真是非常谢谢  谢谢  -嗯  不用客气
- So thank you. Thank you. - Yeah. Sure.
-保重  -好 谢谢
- Take care. - Yeah. Thank you.
你好
Hello?
你好  有人在吗
Hello, anybody home?
-什么事  -我觉得你更应该问“在哪里”
- What? - A better question would be "where?"
比如说“我的封面故事在哪里”
As in "where's my story?"
对不起  等一下
Sorry, love. Two seconds.
-喂  -爸爸  你在哪儿  也不打电话
- Hello? - Daddy, where are you? You didn't call.
对不起  宝贝  爸爸在工作  等会儿打回去给你
Sorry, darlings. Daddy's working. I'll call you back in two seconds.
要快点  快熄灯了
Hurry. It's nearly lights out.
抱歉  Lucinda  别着急
Sorry, Lucinda. Don't worry.
我保证这篇Hannah Montana的文章会
I guarantee this Hannah Montana story is...
Hannah Montana
Hannah Montana!
真不敢相信  爸爸  很高兴我们给你打了这个电话
I can't believe it! Dad! I'm glad we called you.
难以置信  你见到她了吗
I don't believe this! Have you met her yet?
别吵了  孩子们
Not now, girls!
-请一定要帮我们拿到她的签名  -我快晕过去了
- Please get us her autograph! - I'm going to faint!
谁啊  谁在那尖叫啊
Who's that? What's all that screaming?
-亲爱的  我会再给你打电话的  -爸爸 爸爸 一定要记得
- Darlings, I'll call you back. - Daddy, Daddy, make sure you do!
-抱歉 刚说到哪儿了  -Ozzie 我需要一篇绝对丑闻
- Sorry. You were saying? - Ozzie, I want the dirt!
相信我  我全身都是(丑闻和泥浆同音)
Trust me, I'm all over it.
这真是可笑  我也很是可笑
It's kinda funny, so I kinda funny
哦 唱错了
Oh, I messed up. Um...
这真是可笑  我想让可笑走掉
It's kinda funny, so I get funny out
你的脑海里有个声音不停说
There's a voice inside your head saying
你只是...
You just...
你只是赞同了我
You just join me
对不起  别停下  我这就走
Um, I'm sorry. Don't stop. I'm going.
没关系  我只是唱着好玩的
Don't worry about it. I was goofing off.
很高兴你仍然喜欢唱歌
I think it's great you're still doing that singing thing.
唱歌  唱什么歌
Singing thing? What singing thing?
拜托  每个人都知道你最喜欢的就是唱歌
Come on. Everyone knows that's all you ever wanted to do.
而且  你的声音确实很棒
And... you actually got a nice voice.
谢谢  早就有人跟我说过了
Thanks. I've heard that.
那你觉得这首歌怎么样  我写的
What did you think of the song? I wrote it.
-歌  -是啊  我刚刚唱的那首
- Song? - Yeah, that thing I was just singing?
我有说过是我写的吗
Did I mention I wrote it?
听起来大多数音符你都唱对了
And it seems like you got most of the notes right.
所以  很不错啊  Miley
So way to go, Miley.
大多数
"Most"?
-那你为什么不喜欢  -天 我没说过我不喜欢
-So why didn't you like it?  -Jeez, I didn't say I didn't like it.
可你也没说你喜欢
You sure didn't say you did.
-并不是说差  只是不怎么  -好
- It's not bad. It just wasn't... - Good.
没什么内容
About anything.
听不出来你的个性和你的感觉
Doesn't tell me anything about who you are or what you feel.
-你知道我现在的感觉吗  -我能想到
- You know what I'm feeling now? - I've got an idea.
不过抱歉  是你要问的
And sorry, but you asked.
你现在是在忙什么
Why are you bothering with this anyway?
做一笔鸡蛋生意  Ruby和我达成了一个协议
Starting up an egg business. Me and Ruby struck a deal.
我把鸡笼重新建好  我就能去卖那些鸡蛋了
I rebuild the coop, I get to sell the eggs.
重建得干很多活
It's a lot of rebuilding.
你总得从某个地方开始  对吧
Hey, you got to start somewhere, right?
生活就像登山  但是看到的景色总是很美
Life's a climb, but the view is great.
你就只想在Crowley Corners的集市卖些鸡蛋吗
That's all you want to do, is sell eggs in Crowley Corners?
-不然还能卖什么  -我不是那个意思
- Where else am I going to? - That's not what I meant.
我知道你想说什么  你还是不喜欢这里  对吗
I know what you meant. You don't get this place, do you?
-来吧  给马上鞍  -我们要去哪儿
- Come on. Saddle up. - Where are we going?
给你看些  你错过了的东西
To show you... what you're missing.
(Miley Cyrus - Dream)
#帮我个忙#
Do me a favor
#告诉我你对我的想法#
Tell me what you think about me
#告诉我你对未来的计划#
Tell me how you want this to be
#大胆尝试  尽情梦想#
Go out on a limb and just dream
#画一幅画#
Paint a picture
#好好挑选你的颜色#
Choose your colors extra wise
#尤其是我对你的印象#
Especially what you put on my mind
#想象一下触摸到天空会是什么样#
Imagine what it'd be like to touch the sky, yeah, yeah
#喔哦  你的心灵会带我启程#
Whoa oh, your thoughts are gonna pick me up
#这种感觉如此美妙#
Do you know its good to feel so much
#喔  你让我冲入云霄#
Whoa, you got my heads in the clouds
#喔  你让我思绪萦绕#
Whoa, you got me thinking out loud
#你梦到我越多我就越是坚信#
The more you dream about me the more that I believe
#没有什么事情办不到#
That nothing's ever out of reach
#因此  尽情梦想#
So, dream dream dream
#这滋味实在美妙#
It's like the best thing
#只要你尽情幻想#
Every time that you dream, yeah, yeah, yeah
#喔哦  你给了我冒险的勇气#
Whoa, oh, you're giving me the will to try
(本周六晚八点  牧场礼堂举办的音乐之夜  请帮助我们拯救Crowley牧场)
#你可知道  这双眼中充满着欢乐#
Do you know that there's happy in these eyes
#喔  你让我冲入云霄#
Whoa, you got my heads in the clouds
#喔  你让我思绪萦绕#
Whoa, you got me thinking out loud
#你梦到我越多我就越是坚信#
The more you dream about me the more that I believe
#没有什么事情办不到#
That nothing's ever out of reach
#因此  尽情梦想#
So, dream dream dream
我们得走了 募捐会可不能迟到
Hey we should probably get going. We don't want to be late for the fundraiser.
(Billy Ray Cyrus - Back To Tennessee)
#我正在路上#
I'm on the road now,
#我知道自己需要什么#
I know just what I need,
#才能找到回田纳西的路#
To find my way back to Tennessee.
#我正在回家#
I'm coming home now,
#向着南方  如此美妙#
To Southern, it's so sweet,
#找到回家的路 重回你的怀抱#
And find my way back to you and me,
#重新回到田纳西的怀抱#
Find my way back to Tennessee.
好呀  唱得好  老爸
Whoo-hoo! Good job, Daddy!
这就是Robby Ray Stewart  各位  很高兴你能回来  先生
Robby Ray Stewart, everybody. Good to have you back, sir.
-你唱得真是太好了  -谢谢 亲爱的
- You were so great up there. - Thank you, honey.
他这是怎么了  又不是没约会过
What is the matter with him? He's dated before.
也许还是老问题
Maybe it's starting to mean something again.
如果不介意的话  下面是一首慢歌
We're going to slow it down for this next song, if that's all right.
(Taylor Swift - Crazier)
-干嘛  -她喜欢你  你也喜欢她
- What? - She likes you. You like her.
你何必要把所有事都搞得如此复杂
Why do you have to make everything so complicated?
Miley  你不明...
Miley, you just wouldn't unders...
-你怎么知道她喜欢我  -不是那样的话她就是疯了
- How do you know she likes me? - Because she'd be crazy if she didn't.
确实很有道理
You got a good point there.
我看到Lorelai到后面去了
I saw Lorelai go out back.
也许你可以过去帮她解解闷
Maybe you can go help her with the empties or everything.
值得一试
I could try.
#我从不曾被那风吹走  只是任它飘流#
I've never gone with the wind, just let it flow
#任它载着我随意地四处云游#
Let it take me where it wants to go
#直到我迈进你的门#
Till you open the door
#你的世界绚丽缤纷#
There's so much more
Miley 想跳支舞吗
Miley? Would you like to dance?
#未曾见过也闻所未闻#
I'd never seen it before
#我一直试图飞翔  却始终找不到翅膀#
I was tryin' to fly, but I couldn't find wings
刚才我很抱歉
Sorry about that back there.
这次回来完全是为了Miley  而不是为了我
This trip was always supposed to be about Miley. Not really about me.
没有想过可以两者兼顾
Ever think the two might be related?
你说得对  我们的家庭更加亲密了  更加的...
You're right. Our family's closer than most, more...
秘密 我注意到了
Secretive? I've noticed.
她怎么样了
So how's she doing?
我有种感觉她...
I have a feeling she...
我们会一切顺利的
We are gonna be just fine.
#你使我眩晕了 眩晕了 眩晕了#
You make me crazier, crazier, crazier
#宝贝 你让我明白了活着的意义#
Baby, you showed me what living is for
#我再不要隐藏自己#
I don't want to hide anymore
#你荡起我  我飞离了地面  绕着你不停盘旋#
You lift my feet off the ground, you spin me around
#你使我眩晕了  眩晕了#
You make me crazier, crazier
#感觉不停坠落的我啊  迷失于你的双眼#
Feels like I'm falling and I'm lost in your eyes
#你使我眩晕了  眩晕了  眩晕了#
You make me crazier, crazier, crazier
#眩晕了  眩晕了#
Crazier, craizer
(拯救Crowley牧场)
谢谢
Thank you.
Miley  今晚谁都可以唱  你也该上去试试
Miley, you know it's open mike night. You should give it a try.
不  不用了  我是说  我爸...
No. Wait. It's good. I mean, my dad...
-来吧  要开心地玩  -不  不
- Come on. It's all about having fun. - No. No.
-Travis  -看样子又有人要大显身手了
- Travis! - Looks like we got ourselves a taker.
好吧
All right, um...
如果你们不介意的话  我要在乡村乐里加点嘻哈的元素
If you guys don't mind, I'm gonna add a little hip-hop to this hoedown.
好吧  我需要五弦琴上来伴奏
All right, banjo, I'm gonna need you to come on up here.
还有  和声的姑娘们呢  快上来
And where are my girls at? Come on up.
好  开始
All right. Here we go.
碰碰咔  碰嘀咔嘀咔
Boom boom clap boom de clap de clap.
碰碰咔  喔哦哦
Boom boom clap. Whoa, oh, oh
来
Here we go!
#碰碰咔  碰嘀咔嘀咔#
Boom boom clap boom de clap de clap.
#喔哦哦#
Whoa, oh, oh
(Miley Cyrus - Hoedown Throwdown)
#喔哦哦#
Whoa, oh, oh
#一  二  三#
One, two, three
#大家都快站起来#
Everybody, come on off your seats
#我要向你们介绍一种节奏  让你们都能跳起来#
I'm gonna tell you about a beat that's gonna make you move your feet
#我要办一个烧烤秀  告诉你们如何跳舞#
I'll give the barbecue show and tell you how to move
#不管你是五岁还是八十二  所有人都能做到#
If you're five or 82 this is something you can do
#伸手  弯腰  再点两下  乡村然后是嘻哈#
Pop it, lock it, polka-dot it countrify then hip-hop it
#把老鹰放到天空  再扭两下#
Put your hawk in the sky and move side to side
#跳到左边  立正  往后滑#
Jump to the left, stick it, glide
明白了吗 来吧 再来一次
You got it. Come on. OK, one more time.
#伸手  弯腰  再点两下  乡村然后是嘻哈#
Pop it, lock it, polka-dot it countrify then hip-hop it
#把老鹰放到天空  再扭两下#
Put your hawk in the sky and move side to side
#跳到左边  立正  往后滑#
Jump to the left, stick it, glide
#摇摆  再横着走  沿着对角线走两下#
Zigzag across the floor shuffle in diagonal
#当鼓声响起  双手叉腰上#
When the drum hits, hands on your hips
#单脚180度大回旋  然后是  摇摆  跨步滑#
One-footed 180 twist and then a zigzag, step and slide
#靠向左边  手拍三下#
Lean it left, clap three times
#摇摆起来  从头到脚  用尽全身力气  我们就要这样跳#
Shake it out head to toe, throw it all together, that's how we roll
#-来跳乡村舞  -嘻哈舞#
- Do the hoedown - Throwdown
#用尽全身力气  我们就要这样跳#
Throw it all together That's how we roll
#来吧  开始#
Come on. Here we go.
#摇摆  再横着走  沿着对角线走两下#
Zigzag across the floor shuffle in diagonal
#当鼓声响起  双手叉腰上#
When the drum hits, hands on your hips
#单脚180度大回旋  然后是  摇摆 跨步滑#
One-footed 180 twist and then a zigzag, step and slide
#靠向左边  手拍三下#
Lean it left, clap three times
#摇摆起来  从头到脚  用尽全身力气  我们就要这样跳#
Shake it out head to toe, throw it all together, that's how we roll
#-来跳乡村舞  -嘻哈舞#
- Do the hoedown - Throwdown
#用尽全身力气  我们就要这样跳#
Throw it all together That's how we roll
#碰嘀咔嘀咔  碰碰咔#
A- boom de clap de clap Boom boom clap
#来吧  再一次#
Come on. Here we go.
#伸手  弯腰  再点两下  乡村然后是嘻哈#
Pop it, lock it, polka-dot it countrify then hip-hop it
#把老鹰放到天空  再扭两下#
Put your hawk in the sky and move side to side
#跳到左边  立正  往后滑#
Jump to the left, stick it, glide
#摇摆  再横着走  沿着对角线走两下#
Zigzag across the floor shuffle in diagonal
#当鼓声响起  双手叉腰上#
When the drum hits, hands on your hips
#单脚180度大回旋#
One-footed 180 twist
#然后是  摇摆  跨步滑  靠向左边  手拍三下#
And then a zigzag step, slide lean it left, clap three times
#摇摆起来  从头到脚#
Shake it out head to toe
#用尽全身力气  我们就要这样跳#
Throw it all together That's how we roll
#-来跳乡村舞  -嘻哈舞#
- Do the hoedown - Throwdown
#用尽全身力气  我们就要这样跳#
Throw it all together That's how we roll
这就是我们的Miley Stewart  各位
Our very own Miley Stewart, people.
你胆子真大  敢来这里
You got a lot of nerve coming in here.
抱歉  我以为这是个社区集会
I'm sorry. I thought this was a community event.
社区  你根本就不知道这个词是什么意思
Community. You wouldn't even know what that word means.
但我知道你对这个词的理解已经过时了
Well, I know that your idea of it is a thing of the past.
你们今晚筹集到了多少
How much y'all raise tonight?
一千美元
A thousand dollars?
还是两千
Two thousand dollars?
不管是多少  我都会出双倍
Whatever it is, I'll double it.
我们才不要你的钱
We don't want your money.
好啊  反正到最后也无所谓了
At the end of the day it ain't gonna matter.
就算你举办一百次这样的集会也筹集不到
You can have a hundred of these, you ain't gonna raise the money
足以拯救牧场的钱
it's gonna take to save the Meadows,
除非是甲壳虫乐队来办募捐演唱会
not unless The Beatles show up for a benefit concert.
等等  好像难度比较大
Oh, wait. Small problem.
你们早一天接受现实  也就早一天
The sooner y'all accept the inevitable, the sooner we...
Miley认识Hannah Montana
Miley knows Hannah Montana.
-她是谁  -她冲浪时救过她的命
- Who's that? - She saved her life surfing.
她们是好朋友  她会来帮我们的  对吧
They're best friends. She could help us out, right?
办一场演唱会  那会筹到很多很多钱
Throw a concert. That would raise a ton of money.
对  就这么办  快打电话给她
Yeah! Yeah! Do it. Yeah. Call her.
那我就打个电话给她
I guess I could give her a call.
Hannah Montana认识Miley
Hannah Montana knows Miley?
天啊  是Hannah Montana  我爱你  Hannah
Oh, my gosh! It's Hannah Montana! I love you, Hannah!
天啊  她来了  没想到她真的会来
Oh, my gosh. She's here. I didn't think she'd actually come.
谢谢  谢谢谢谢谢谢  给我一个拥抱  谢谢
Thank you! Thank you, thank you, thank you. Give me a hug. Thank you.
太乡村了
So rustic.
-我喜欢 Miley  -谢谢
- I love it, Miley. - Thanks.
这个“明星拯救故乡”的点子太棒了
This whole "pop star saves hometown" angle is genius.
虽然没有棒到好让我原谅你把我扔在纽约
Not so genius that I forgive you for ditching me in New York
还差点让我丢了饭碗  但还是很棒
and almost costing me my job, but genius nevertheless.
你肯定是姥姥了
So you must be Granny.
真可爱  看看这个地方
Adorable. Oh, look at this place.
这实在是太...  怎么说来着
It's just so, um... And, uh...
-这里一直都有这种味道吗  -差不多吧
- It always smell like this? - Pretty much.
失陪了
Excuse me.
Lilly  我太抱歉了  你是我最最要好的朋友
Lilly, I am so sorry. You are the best friend I have ever had.
当我想到你可能不会再跟我说话
When I thought you weren't gonna talk to me,
-我可能会永远失去你  -你就是想甩也甩不掉我
- that I might lose you forever... - Hey you couldn't lose me even if you wanted to.
很好  因为我不想
Good, because I don't want to.
另外  抱歉我告诉那个记者了
And... sorry about talking to that reporter guy.
什么  Lilly是你告诉那个记者的  你怎么可以
What? Lilly, you're the one that talked to the reporter? How could you?
嘿 我觉得现在应该是我们互相表达歉意的时间
Hey, I thought this was one of those "you're sorry, I'm sorry" moments.
没有错  我确实很抱歉
It is, and I am.
我发誓再也不会让Hannah影响到我们的友谊
And I swear Hannah'll never come between us again.
好
OK.
-Miley  -什么
- Miley? - Yeah?
我能进去跟你和Hannah谈谈吗
Could I come in and talk to you and Hannah for a minute?
-你来当Hannah  -不  你来当
- You be Hannah. - No, you're Hannah.
-我不行  你来当Hannah  别吵了  -Miley
- I can't. No, you be Hannah. Stop it. - Miley?
有很重要的事
It's kind of important.
-不行  -回去
- No. - Back.
别再对我这样
Stop doing this.
住手
Stop!
请进
Come in.
我很抱歉  我不知道
I'm so sorry. I didn't realize...
别担心  这只是小小的放松
No worries. This is just a little de-stressing.
这能帮助Hannah调整时差
It helps with Hannah's jet lag.
时差  但是加州到这里只有两个小时
Jet lag? But California's only two hours...
没错  但是Hannah只从西往东飞
Yes. But you see Hannah only flies west to east,
所以...  她的时间反而变早了
so... she gains time.
有时她需要绕地球飞一大圈
She sometimes has to go the long way around.
她其实越来越年轻了
She's actually getting younger.
-你有什么事吗  -啊  是的
- Did you want something? - Uh, yeah.
嗨  Hannah
Hi, Hannah.
我是Lorelai  我们都非常感谢你这次能来
I'm Lorelai. And we are just all so grateful that you're here.
那没...
Oh, well...
脚部按摩
Foot massage.
非常洛杉矶
Very L.A.
-Miley 你在上面吗  -他还不知道
- Miley, you up there? - He doesn't know.
Hannah已经来了  他肯定会非常兴奋的
That Hannah's here. He is going to be so excited.
-我去告诉他  -那我继续帮她按摩
- Let me tell him. - I'll take over.
不  Hannah把我当成了她的私人...
No. See Hannah considers me her personal, you know...
像这种事情  好吧
There's these things that... Fine.
但是不能说话
Hey, but no talking.
镇长今天晚上想举办盛大的宴会来欢迎你
So the mayor wants to throw this big bash in your honor this evening.
我还特地为了你让他们空运了龙虾
And I've had lobsters flown in and everything just for you.
希望它们不会有太多时差
I hope they don't get too jet-lagged.
总之
Anyway...
爸
Dad!
-爸  你在干吗  -帮你姥姥修水槽啊
- Dad, what are you doing? - Fixing your grandma's gutter.
帮我扶着梯子  别把南瓜踩坏了
Hold the ladder for me. And don't squish the squashes.
爸  快下来  我有急事  现在立刻下来
Dad please come down. It's an emergency. I need you right now.
那你是同意了
Is that a yes?
噢  这实在太棒了  哇
Oh! Oh, that's fantastic. Wow.
Lorelai为什么会在帮Hannah按摩脚
What is Lorelai doing rubbing Hannah's feet?
-严格来说  那是Lilly的脚  -呆在这里
- Technically, they're Lilly's. - Stay.
爸  爸  都安排好了  我已经和Derrick谈过了...
Dad. Dad, we're all set. I talked to Derrick, and...
-他怎么了  -嘘  过来
- What's with him? - Shh. Come here.
嘿  Lorelai
Hey. Lorelai.
-你干吗不让Hannah休  -嘘  她好像睡着了
- Why don't you let Hannah rest... - Shh, I think she's asleep.
可怜的小家伙  要倒时差
Poor thing. Jet lag.
她总是从西部飞到东部
She only flies west to east.
什么  这是我这辈子听到过的最蠢的事了
What? That's the stupidest thing I've ever heard in my life.
某种名人的习惯吧
Some kind of celebrity thing.
但是她同意了  她答应参加镇长宴会
But she said yes. She's coming to the mayor's dinner.
我的工作就是把她请过去  而她答应了
It was my job to get her there, and she is coming.
-好极了  -你也会去的  对吧
- Great. - You're going, right?
我不知道
I don't know.
你这是在邀请我吗
Is this you asking?
是啊  我觉得应该算是吧
Yeah. I think it might be.
那么这就是我的答复
Then this is me accepting.
-我觉得他们要接吻了  -太好了
- I think they're gonna kiss. - Yes!
上啊  老爸  上啊  老爸
Go, Daddy! Go, Daddy!
这儿确实有点热啊  我还是把窗子打开吧
Certainly is getting hot in here. I think I'll open up the window.
我不想让大明星睡在闷热的屋子里
I don't want her to sleep in a stuffy room.
老爸  老爸
Daddy, Daddy.
哦  Jackson
Oh, Jackson!
你没事吧  当心  梯子
Are you OK? Watch it. Ladder.
你没事吧  我来帮你
Are you all right? Let me help you.
我没事  我没事
I'm OK. I'm OK.
这东西尝起来  绿色健康  里面放了什么
These taste... healthy. What's in them?
南瓜
Squash.
喔  我正想要个牛仔
Ooh. I want a cowboy.
不好意思  人家已经名草有主了
Sorry. That one's taken.
-真的  -是呀
- Really? - Yeah.
也不算
No.
可能吧  我不清楚  看来我们只能做普通朋友
Maybe. I don't know. It looks like we're going to be just friends.
但他还没见到Hannah呢
But he hasn't met Hannah yet.
来吧
Come on.
那么 Ha...
So, Ha...
Ha...
快看呐  是Hannah Montana
Hey, look! It's Hannah Montana!
你好  抱歉  我...  没看到你
Oh, hi. Sorry, I... I didn't see you.
我叫Travis  谢谢你能来
I'm Travis. Thanks for coming.
好啊  乐意效劳  这位是Lilly  她是我的助理
Yeah, happy to help. This is Lilly. She's my assistant.
执行助理
Executive assistant.
欢迎来Crowley Corners
Welcome to Crowley Corners.
如果有人能够  带我们到处逛逛那是再好不过了
It sure would be nice to have someone to... show us around.
-真会说话  -怎么了
- Real smooth. - What?
我恐怕不是合适的人选  不过还是很高兴能见到你们
Look, I really don't think I'm your guy. But nice to meet you.
不  上  上
No, go. Go!
那么  你在装卫星信号接收器
So... putting up a satellite dish.
这是个鸟池
It's a birdbath.
我就知道
I knew that.
Lilly  你能否去找一下这间漂亮房子的主人
Lilly, could you go find the owner of this fine house
还有让他们了解一下我的饮食习惯
and run them through my dietary needs?
快去吧  助理
Go. Assist.
好吧
OK.
那么  你和Miley挺亲密的吧
So, you and Miley are pretty close, huh?
亲密到你无法想象
You have no idea.
如果你觉得这是个私人问题可以不用回答  但是...
You don't have to answer if you think this is too personal, but...
你觉得如果我约她出去她会答应吗
you think she'd go out with me if I asked?
你想约Miley出去
You want to go out with Miley?
不是  你可能会很吃惊  别理解错了  可是...
No, you'd be a real prize. Don't get me wrong, but...
可是Miley她...
But Miley...
她一在我身边我就会笑个不停
I can't help but smile when I'm around her.
我无时不刻不在想着她  还有我...
I think about her all the time. And I...
你应该约她出去
You should go ask her out.
真的吗
Really?
说得对  没错  我要现在就去问她
Yeah. Yeah, I'm going to do that right now.
不不不  等一下
No, no. No. Excuse me.
你现在不能进去  她不在家  Miley  你看  她不在家
You can't go in there. She's not home. Miley! Miley! See, she's not home.
她说了去什么马厩  给蓝仔洗澡之类的话
She said something about going to the barn and brushing Blue Jeans.
你应该去那儿问她  快去  快去  快去  快  再见
You should go ask her there. Go, go, go! Go. Goodbye.
快去
Go!
-走慢点  急性子  -我要走了  我要走了
- Slow down, hot stuff. - Got to go. Got to go. Got to go.
Miley
Miley?
Miley  Miley  你在...
Miley! Miley, are you...?
嘿  大懒虫
Hey, slacker.
嘿
Uh, hey.
我刚才在和你朋友Hannah聊天来着
I was just talking to your friend, Hannah.
而且我们还谈到了你
Actually, we were talking about you.
哦  是吗  那么你到这儿来想说什么
Oh, really. Was there something you wanted to say
还是要问我什么或者要告诉我什么
or ask me or talk to me about?
嗯  我知道你很快就要回去了
Well, I know you're going home soon.
是啊  快了  说的对  Travis  接着说啊
Yeah, I am. That's right, Travis, keep going.
这个...
Um, well...
我在想你是否愿意和我一起共进晚餐
I was wondering if maybe you would like to go to dinner with me this evening.
好的 没问题
OK. Sure.
反正我也没别的计划  这主意听起来挺不错的
I don't think I have any other plans, so sounds good.
-好啊  -好啊
- Cool. - Cool.
太好了
Cool.
现在你说对了  就是这件
Now you're talking. Oh, that is the one.
是的  可能吧  但是她不能去
Yeah, it would be, but she's not going.
我不能去是什么意思
What do you mean I can't go?
你可是答应了Lorelai的
You're the one that promised Lorelai that
Hannah将会是今晚镇长家的什么龙虾大餐的特邀嘉宾
Hannah would be the guest of honor at the mayor's lobster hoo-hah tonight.
-实际上是Lilly答应的  -实际上是Hannah答应的
- Actually, Lilly did. - Actually, Hannah did.
但是我答应了Travis
But I promised Travis.
知道吗  你自己的烂摊子你自己收拾
You know what? Then I'll just leave it up to you.
你觉得怎么对就怎么做
You do whatever you think is right.
但是...
But...
是Hannah Montana
It's Hannah Montana!
能给我签个名吗  Hannah Montana
Can I have your autograph, Hannah Montana?
笑一个
Smile.
-好  -好极了
- Yeah! - Perfect.
Miley在哪儿  这会儿她应该到了
Where's Miley? She should be here by now.
她得了东海岸-西尼罗河综合征
Hon, she's got East Coast-West Nile disease.
-小家伙一直在旅行呢  -对
- That sucker's traveling. - Yeah.
现在请大家就坐
If everybody could please take their seats.
-对  请各位坐好  -请对号入座
- Yes, be seated, everybody. - Find their place card there.
请允许我真诚地表明我的心情
And let me just say that, honestly,
有幸能够请到你们这些社会精英
to have someone of your talents,
还有  Hannah Montana小姐  如果你
well, Miss Montana, Hannah, if you will,
明天能够举办一场演唱会
your offer of a concert tomorrow
拯救Crowley牧场于水火当中
to save Crowley Meadows from such a sad fate,
那么  我们这个偏远小镇将会感激不尽
well, our humble little corner of the world can't thank you enough.
如果你有任何需要我本人
And if there's ever anything that myself
或者Crowley Corners镇人民的帮助
or the good people of Crowley Corners can do for you,
你有任何需要  我们都会...
anything you need, all you have to do is...
她人呢
Where did she go?
我只是想要见见我的粉丝
Need. I just need to check on my fans.
Hannah  Hannah
Hannah, Hannah...
你看  但是实际上我要去趟洗手间
See? But what I really need is I need to go to the bathroom.
我很急  Lilly  陪我一起去  现在就走
I need to go. Lilly, come with me. Right now!
化妆用品  衣服  都准备好了  去吧
Makeup, clothes, it's all in there. Go.
-我马上就回来  帮我打掩护  -好的
- I'll be right back. Cover for me. - OK.
-对不起我来晚了  -不  你没来晚  是我来早了
- Sorry I'm late. - You're not late. I was early.
-这个送给你  -谢谢
- I got you these. - Thank you.
你只戴了一边的耳环
You do know you only have one earring?
洛杉矶就流行这个
Trendy L.A. Thing.
-我想你很快就要回去了  -是的
- I guess you're going back there soon? - Yeah.
-那我就直说吧  -直说好了
- I'm going to go ahead and jump. - Please jump.
Miley...
Well, Miley...
在你临走之前...
Before you leave...
我只想...
...I just...
我很想让你知道我对你的感觉
I really want you to know how I feel about you.
有什么急事吗
Is everything all right?
我必须接这个电话  抱歉  一会儿就好
I really should take this. I'm sorry, it will just be a second.
我保证
I swear.
可能在后面信号会更好
I'll probably get better reception in the back.
收到两格信号  三格
I got two bars. Three bars.
四格
Four bars!
Hannah Hannah Hannah Hannah
Hannah. Hannah. Hannah. Hannah.
既然我们的主宾回来了  那就开动吧
Now that our guest of honor has returned, dig in!
这个龙虾可真大  不是吗
That's a heck of a crawdaddy, isn't it?
Hannah  你肯定有很多精彩的故事可以与大家分享
So, Hannah, you must have a lot of wonderful stories to tell.
哪有
Not really.
我是说真是举不胜举
I mean there are just so many.
但是  我不想让今晚全都以我为中心
But I don't want this evening to be all about me.
我是说  每个人的故事都很重要  对吧  Jackson
I mean, everybody's stories are important, right, Jackson?
你刚刚开始上大学
You just started college.
-说说你的课程吧  -对啊  我的课程
- Tell us about your classes. - Yeah, my classes. Uh...
我非常喜欢...
I really like...
我最喜欢的部分就是...
I think my favorite part is...
老爸  你的儿子已经长大成人了
Dad, that your little boy is growing up into a man.
噢  我的餐巾掉了
Oops, dropped my napkin.
Harlow
Harlow!
-你在搞什么鬼  -我在找我的雪貂
- What are you doing? - Looking for a ferret.
-你又在干什么  -试着挽回我的第一段成熟的感情
- What are you doing? - Trying to have my first mature relationship.
快坐回去
Now get back up there.
找到了
Found it.
-我要吃龙虾  -菜单上没有龙虾
- I'm having the lobster. - It's not on the menu.
是啊
Right.
对不起  这几天有点怪  但是...
Sorry. It's been a weird couple of days, but...
是啊
Yeah.
我知道你有些话你想对我说
And I think I know some of the things you want to tell me.
是啊
Yeah?
我也有很多事情想告诉你
There are so many things I want to tell you, too, and...
只能再等等了
That's just going to have to wait.
我要去再检查一下我点的龙虾
I need to go double-check on my lobsters.
-喝汽水能把那个东西搞吐出来  -坐下  够了
- Club soda will take that out. - Sit! That's enough.
任何人不得离开餐桌  任何人
No one is getting up from this table. No one.
有谁要甜点吗
Dessert, anyone?
你们肯定都听说过火焰雪山
I'm sure you've all heard of baked Alaska.
我们有田纳西火烧煎蛋卷
We give you Tennessee flambe.
镇长先生  我想您该做结束致辞了吧
Mr. Mayor, I assume that you'd like to say a few final words?
哦  对对
Oh, yes, yes.
很多人不知道田纳西火烧煎蛋卷的真正发明者是...
Not many people know that the Tennessee flambe was actually invented by...
给我过来
Come here.
-镇长先生  -我可抓住你了
- Mr. Mayor! - I got you now.
Harlow
Harlow!
着火了
We got a fire!
该死的
Dang flam it!
进展很顺利  不是吗
This has all gone very well. Don't you think?
不好意思  借过一下  借过
Sorry, excuse me. Excuse me.
Travis  请听我解释
Travis, please let me explain.
解释什么
Explain what?
解释你一直在耍我玩
That you've been making fun of me?
嘲笑我  一直都在欺骗我
Laughing at me? Lying to me this whole time?
我一直对你坦诚相见  告诉你我的感受
I was honest with you. I told you how I felt.
-我也是一样的  -不  你没有
- And I feel the same way. - No, you don't.
因为我永远不像你对我这样对待你
Because I would have never treated you like that.
你知道吗  Miley  Hannah  无论你是谁
You know what, Miley... Hannah, whoever you are?
我们都结束了
We're done.
Travis
Travis!
Travis  求你了
Travis, please.
-你都看见了  -是的  我看见了
- Did you see? - Yeah, I saw.
Robby Ray  是你在那儿吗
Robby Ray, is that you down there? Uh...
现在不行  Lorelai  我们家人之间出了点问题
Not now, Lorelai. I've got some family stuff going on.
抱歉  只是  这整晚就是场灾难
I'm sorry. It's just this whole evening was a disaster.
我所策划的一切  就被那个女孩这么毁了
I just organized the whole thing, and then that girl comes in and ruins it.
我不在乎她是不是来一场大型音乐会的
I don't care if she is here for a big concert.
她的生活很复杂  我知道这很难理解  但是...
She's got a complicated life. I know it's hard to understand, but...
到底是怎么回事  Robby Ray
What's going on, Robby Ray?
我真的没时间听秘密和谎言
I really don't have any time for secrets and lies.
我不知道和有很多秘密和谎言的男人在一起会不会快乐
I don't know if I could be happy with somebody comfortable living in them.
我知道  你的想法我理解
I know. You shouldn't have to be.
我应该告诉你事实
I should have told you the truth.
事实就是...
The truth is that...
我现在还没准备好接受一个人
...I just don't have any place in my life for a relationship right now.
我不能分心  Miley和我  我们还有一些事要去解决
There's no room. Miley and me, we've got to sort through some things.
她需要我  我必须要在她身边
And she needs me. And I kind of need to be there for her.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我也很抱歉
Well, me too then.
抱歉
Me too.
Hannah Hannah Hannah Hannah
Hannah. Hannah. Hannah. Hannah.
嘿  小毛毛虫
Hey, caterpillar.
谢谢
Thanks.
不客气
No problem.
-你生气了吗  -不  我没有  你呢
- Are you mad? - No, I'm not mad. You?
没生气
No.
-那首歌怎么样了  -不知道  我还没把握
- How's the song coming? - I don't know. I'm not sure yet.
是关于什么的
What's it about?
你
You.
我
Me.
我们
Us.
我能听听吗
Can I hear it?
(Miley Cyrus And Billy Ray Cyrus - Butterfly Fly Away)
#你为我把被子盖好  把灯关掉#
You tucked me in, turned out the light
#让我安然入睡#
Kept me safe and sound at night
#小女孩需要这样被宠#
Little girls depend on things like that
#你替我梳洗打扮#
Brushed my teeth and combed my hair
#开车载我去任何地方#
Had to drive me everywhere
#需要你的时候你总在我身旁#
You were always there when I looked back
#你一个人照顾我#
You had to do it all alone
#还要为生计奔波#
Make a living, make a home
#那一定十分艰难#
It must have been as hard as it could be
#当我无法入睡时#
And when I couldn't sleep at night
#可怕的东西也不会来#
Scared things wouldn't turn out right
#因为你会握着我的手对我唱#
You would hold my hand and sing to me
和我唱这部分 爸爸
Sing with me on this part, Daddy.
#树上有只毛毛虫#
Caterpillar in the tree
#不知以后会怎样#
How you wonder who you'll be
#哪怕总是走不远  你也一直有梦想#
Can't go far, but you can always dream
#祝你梦想能实现#
Wish you may and wish you might
#别担心  抓紧我#
Don't you worry, hold on tight
#我保证  有一天#
I promise you there will come a day
#你会变成蝴蝶飞起来#
Butterfly, fly away
#蝴蝶快飞吧#
#有了翅膀  不要迟疑#
You got your wings, now you can't stay
#带着梦想飞起来#
Take those dreams and make them all come true
#蝴蝶呀  蝴蝶呀  蝴蝶呀#
Butterfly, butterfly, butterfly
#蝴蝶快飞吧#
Butterfly, fly away
-Miley  -是  怎么了
- Miley! - Yes! What?
Miley
Miley!
-你还好吧  -你难道不知道
- Are you OK? - Don't you know better
别人在鸡舍上面睡觉的时候最好别对她大叫吗
than to yell at someone asleep on top of a chicken coop?
现在知道了
I do now.
这是你干的吗  一晚上都在这儿
Did you do this? Were you out here all night?
只是有点小难  如此而已
Just a little hard work. That's all.
生活就像攀登
Life's a climb.
是时候了
Is it time?
是的  时间到了
Yeah, it's time.
走吧
Let's go.
我们刚从一个匿名的捐款人那儿
We received a one-thousand-dollar contribution
-筹到了1000美元  -就快够了
- from an anonymous benefactor! - We're getting there.
太棒了  这太了不起了  演唱会见
Isn't it awesome? This is terrific! See you at the concert.
-请过去  请过去  -请你后退
- Coming through. Coming through. - Stay back!
我不是经纪人  也不是经理  我是她姥姥
I'm not the agent, I'm not the manager, I'm the grandma.
-货真价实的  -她可以进去
- I'm the real deal. - She's OK.
祝你愉快  夫人
Have a good day, ma'am.
亲爱的  我都不知道该说什么了
Whew, honey. I had no idea.
难怪他们把你藏在这里
No wonder they hide you away in this camper thingie.
每次都这么疯狂吗
Is it always this crazy?
一直都是
Always.
我知道这很难
Well, I know the getting here was hard,
但你在做一件好事
but what you're doing is a good thing.
你应该为此骄傲
You should be proud of that.
我为你骄傲
I know I am.
这是我妈妈的
This was my mom's?
是的
Yeah.
她也会为你骄傲的
She'd be proud of you too.
没错
Yeah.
谢谢
Thanks.
我该把它放在这儿  这样就能...
Um, I'm just gonna put it in here so I can...
这样它无论何时都能陪伴我了
So I can have it in my pocket with my show and everything.
这样很好  离你很近
That's good, close to you.
谢谢你  我爱你
Thank you. I love you.
我爱你  亲爱的
I love you, darling.
Hannah Hannah Hannah Hannah
Hannah! Hannah! Hannah! Hannah!
驾  驾
Ya! Ya!
(Hannah Montana - Rock Star)
#走在学校门廊里#
Sometimes I walk a little faster
#我的步伐有点快#
In the school hallway
#只是为了靠近你#
Just to get next to you
#早上多花些时间#
Some days I spend a little extra time in the morning
#穿得好点吸引你#
Dress to impress you
#猜你没有注意到#
Guess you don't notice
#猜你不需要这个#
Guess you don't need this
#遗憾地是你都没看到#
Sad you're not seein' what you're missin'
#你看我表面很害羞#
On the outside shyin' away
#内心的声音在呐喊#
On the inside dyin' to say
#我不普通#
I'm unusual
#也不典型#
Not so typical
#我会在这里等待你#
Way too smart to be waiting around
#我会打太极#
Taichi practicing
#滑雪拿冠军#
Snowboard champion
#我不仅能修你汽车的车盖#
I could fix the flat on your car
#我还能成为一名摇滚巨星#
I might even be a rock star
我办不到
I can't do this.
对不起
Sorry.
我喜欢当Hannah  但是我不能再这样做了
I've loved being Hannah, but I just don't think I can do it anymore.
至少在这儿不行  不能这样对待你们
At least not here, not with you guys.
这是...  这是我的家乡
See, this is... this is home.
这里是生我养我的地方  是我的家
This is where I'm from. This is family.
也只有家人才能为你作出如此多的牺牲
And there's only so many sacrifices you can ask a family to make.
上一次站在这个舞台上时我才六岁
The last time I stood on this stage I was six.
我是...
I was...
我就是Miley
I was just Miley.
现在仍然是
And I still am.
这就是...
Hi. It's...
这就是我
It's me.
我伤害了很多人  但是  我不是故意的
I've hurt a lot of people, but... I didn't mean to.
如果还不算太迟的话
And... if it's not too late...
我真想在得到一个机会
...I sure would like a second chance.
我知道你们都是来听Hannah演唱的  但是...
I know you all came to hear Hannah, but...
如果你们不介意  我为你们写了一首歌
...if you don't mind, I've written y'all a song.
是我的个人感受
It's kind of personal.
是我在这两周体验到的
It's about what I've learned over the last couple weeks.
生活就像攀登
Life's a climb.
但风景是美好的
But the view is great.
(Miley Cyrus - The Climb)
#眼前依稀浮现#
I can almost see it
#萦绕心头的那个梦境#
That dream I'm dreamin' but
#脑海里却响起一个声音#
There's a voice inside my head saying
#你永远也不会到达那里#
you'll never reach it
#我迈出的每一步#
Every step I'm taking
#我做过的每件事#
Every move I make feels
#无不使我迷失方向#
Lost with no direction
#开始动摇的  是我的信念#
My faith is shakin
#可我  我还是要继续求索#
But I, I gotta keep tryin
#还是要挺胸抬头  阔步前行#
Gotta keep my head held high
#总会有下一座山峦#
There's always gonna be another mountain
#在等我去将它征服#
I'm always gonna wanna make it move
#爬上山会很难#
Always gonna be an uphill battle
#有时我会失败#
Sometimes I'm gonna have to lose
#不在于我要用多久才能抵达峰顶#
Ain't about how fast I get there
#不在于山那边到底是怎样的风景#
Ain't about what's waitin' on the other side
#这就是攀登#
It's the climb
#我面对的每个挑战#
The struggles I'm facing
#我抓住的每次机遇#
The chances I'm taking
#有时会令我一败涂地#
Sometimes might knock me down but
#却决不会磨去我的意志#
No I'm not breaking
#或许我不懂其中的意义#
I may not know it
#但这些时刻却会成为#
But these are the moments that
#我一辈子可以珍藏的回忆#
I'm gonna remember most, yeah
#只管继续前进#
Just gotta keep going
#我要  我要变得坚强#
And I, I gotta be strong
#只须奋力前行  因为#
Just keep pushing on 'cause
#总会有下一座山峦#
There's always gonna be another mountain
#在等我去将它征服#
I'm always gonna wanna make it move
#爬上山会很难#
Always gonna be an uphill battle
#有时我会失败#
Sometimes I'm gonna have to lose
#不在于我要用多久才能抵达顶峰#
Ain't about how fast I get there
#不在于山那边到底是怎样的风景#
Ain't about what's waitin on the other side
#这就是攀登#
It's the climb
#总会有下一座山峦#
There's always gonna be another mountain
#在等我去将它征服#
I'm always gonna wanna make it move
#爬上山会很难#
Always gonna be an uphill battle
#有时我会失败#
Sometimes you're gonna have to lose
#不在于我要用多久才能抵达顶峰#
Ain't about how fast I get there
#不在于山那边到底是怎样的风景#
Ain't about what's waitin on the other side
#这就是攀登#
It's the climb
#继续前行#
Keep on moving
#继续攀登#
Keep climbing
#坚守信念#
Keep the faith
#宝贝#
Baby
#这一切就是#
It's all about
#这一切就是攀登#
It's all about the climb
#坚守你的信念#
Keep your faith
谢谢你们让我成为Hannah
Thanks for letting me live my Hannah.
拜
Bye.
求你
Please.
求你变回Hannah吧  我们会保守你的秘密的
Please be Hannah. We'll keep your secret.
抱歉  我不能  太迟了
I'm sorry, I can't. It's too late.
你当然可以
Sure, you can!
请再戴上假发  否则你永远不会有正常的生活
Put the wig back on. You'll never have a normal life if you don't!
Hannah是你的一部分  别让她走
Hannah's a part of you! Don't let her go!
Hannah Hannah Hannah Hannah
Hannah! Hannah! Hannah! Hannah!
请不要这样
No, please.
-快来人  阻止他  -叫保安
- Somebody, stop him! - Call security!
当心  再往前走一步我就按“发送”
Watch it! One more step and I hit "send. "
-别这样做  -抱歉  但这世上没有什么能
- Don't do it. - Sorry, nothing on Earth'll
-阻止我...  -爸爸  爸爸  爸爸
- stop me from... - Daddy! Daddy! Daddy!
Phoebe  Clarissa  你们在这儿干什么
Phoebe, Clarissa, what are you doing?
全是这位漂亮女士安排的  两张免费的门票
This nice lady sorted it all out. Two free tickets.
前排位置  太棒了
Upper class. It was brilliant!
我认为女孩们会很喜欢两张免费的票
I thought the girls'd appreciate a couple of free tickets.
我们来晚了吗  她还会再去唱吗
We too late? She going to sing again?
真不敢相信就来晚了一步
I can't believe that I'm only one degree away...
Hannah Hannah Hannah
Hannah! Hannah! Hannah!
-我的天  Hannah Montana  -真的是她
- My gosh! It's Hannah Montana! - It's really her!
-你就在那儿 而我在这儿 -真不敢相信
- You're right there! I'm here! - I can't believe it!
我真的很喜欢你  我们是你的忠实粉丝
I really love you. We're your biggest fans ever, really.
你不会毁掉他们的梦想吧
You're not going to destroy their dreams, are you?
那正是Hannah的一切
That's what Hannah's all about.
-你会那样写吗  -我一定是在做梦  掐我一下
- Is that your story? - I must be dreaming! Pinch me!
不  我不会这样写
No, that's not my story.
-哦  我的天呐  -女儿们
- Oh, my gosh! - Girls!
-记下来  Lucinda  -你说吧  Ozzie
- Get this down, Lucinda. - Fire away, Ozzie.
《别致》杂志
Bon Chic magazine
是一本可恶卑鄙的女恶魔经营的  以造成别人不幸为生的杂志
is run by a wretched, soulless succubus who preys on the misfortune of others,
我再也不能忍受它了
and I'm not going to put up with it any longer!
Ozzie  Ozzie  回来...
Ozzie! Ozzie! Come...
我刚辞职了
Think I just quit.
来吧  我们去前排  我想Hannah还有歌要唱
Come on. Let's go out front. I think Hannah's got more songs in her.
谢谢  伙计
Thanks, partner.
-各位  请待在原地  -Miley
- Everybody, stay where you are. - Miley!
我们还有很多歌要奉上
We got lots more music for you.
还记得我曾经喜欢你  还说都过去了的话吗
Remember that crush I had on you, and I said I was over it?
是的
Yeah.
快直说吧
Please jump.
远没过去
So not over it.
好极了
Right on!
(Hannah Montana - You'll Always Find Your Way Back Home)
#快快醒来  今天是雨中的星期一#
You wake up it's raining and its Monday
#似乎又是糟糕的一天#
Looks like one of those rough days
#要迟到了  赶快出发#
Times up your late again so get out the door
#有时你想逃跑#
Sometimes you feel like runnin'
#投身一个全新的生活#
Find a whole new life and jump in
#来吧  尽情跳起来#
Let go, get up and hit the dance floor
#心情不好  无人陪伴时#
Cause when I'm feeling down and I'm feelin' all alone.
#我知道哪里才是我的归宿#
I always got a place where I can go.
#因为我知道#
Cause I know
#你可以改变你的发型#
You can change your hair
#你可以换掉你的衣服#
And you can change your clothes
#你可以改变你的想法#
You can change your mind
#这是不言而喻的事实#
that's just the way it goes
#你可以说再见也可以说你好#
You can say goodbye and you can say hello
#但你总会找到你的归途#
But you'll always find your way back home
#你可以改变你的风格#
You can change your style
#你可以换了你的牛仔裤#
You can change your jeans
#你可以学着飞翔#
You can learn to fly
#你可以追逐你的梦想#
And you can chase your dreams
#你可以放声大笑或大哭#
You can laugh or cry
#不过大家都看在眼里#
but everybody knows
#你总会找到你的归途#
You'll always find your way back home
#是的  他们完全知道你是谁#
Yeah they know exactly who you are
#在哪儿你才是真正的超级明星#
Where the real you is a superstar
#你知道那不会太遥远#
You know that it's never too far away
#你可以改变你的发型#
You can change your hair
#你可以换掉你的衣服#
You can change your clothes
#你可以改变你的想法#
You can change your mind
#这是不言而喻的事实#
that's just the way it goes
#你可以说再见也可以说你好#
You can say goodbye and you can say hello
#但你总会找到你的归途#
But you'll always find your way back
#你可以改变你的发型#
You can change your hair
#你可以换掉你的衣服#
And you can change your clothes
#你可以改变你的想法#
You can change your mind
#这是不言而喻的事实#
That's just the way it goes
#你可以说再见也可以说你好#
You can say goodbye and you can say hello
#但你总会找到你的归途#
But you'll always find your way back home
#你可以改变你的风格#
You can change your style
#你可以换了你的牛仔裤#
And you can change your jeans
#你可以学着飞翔#
You can learn to fly
#你可以追逐你的梦想#
And you can chase your dreams
#你可以放声大笑或大哭#
You can laugh or cry
#不过大家都看在眼里#
but everybody knows
#你总会找到你的归途#
You'll always find your way back home
#你总会#
You'll always
#你总会找到你的#
You'll always find your way
#你总会找到你的归途#
You'll always find your way back home
谢谢观赏！
-==本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献==-
欢迎登录www.Deefun.com
翻译： love0forever  WaitinZ  Lenefan
Spike Dai  pppker  Chester.Lee
-==本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献==-
校对： WaitinZ  loveforever  后期： love0forever
特别鸣谢： superjasson  LK歌词组
结束
And cut it!